some
thoughts You know now that the
Patriots have completed the the
draft have they done their uh
street
free agents yet? Well we have a
bunch of reported street free
agents We'll go over some of
those
those Yeah official Twitter
machine It's Mike Re had no
official signings. Okay So we'll
talk about those We'll talk
about who they drafted Who Who's
your Who do you think
will be the the first to make an
impact Uh all of that your
calls your emails in the next
two hours here in Pages
Unfiltered it's Mike it's Evan
it's Paul it's
me it's Matt in the booth So I
hear Matt they're
giggling. I think that's him
grimacing from back pain. That's
That's Marines. He has
back pain. Oh yeah. What Just
carrying us all weekend. Well
he's a Marine He fought in
Afghanistan so he's
he's got a lot of degenerative.
I haven't told you yet Fred I
need back surgery I'm going on
Friday to see the
neurosurgeon. Really What's
going on your brain with you? I
going to your brain with you? I
I have uh two discs touching
each other and they're pinching
nerves They got to put a balloon
in between the discs. Oh man
they got to make them compact
discs It's bad. Oh I'll only be
out for a week. You've inspired
me to come in Don't worry for
me. Okay All right You come in
on like a stretcher in traction
Just reaching over working the
board. All right So um any
lingering thoughts over the from
over
the weekend? No I just I just
say this is my favorite part of
the draft when you just like you
know you guys make fun of me for
my my nerd my nerd depth chart
that I keep that admittedly as
Evan can see and uh no I just
love nothing more than lining
those guys up plugging them in
You know even the UDFAs
plugging them in and then it's
like all right this is pretty
much the roster You know maybe
one or two additions uh down the
road but um it's just good to
finally get past the team
building point and really start
to to think about OTAAS and
vacations and then training camp
It's coming quick.
So as the roster stands right
right now do you feel that
there's any area of the team
where you'd say they can't go
into the season like this? No, I
don't think think so either. No
I don't. Yeah even me? Yeah. I
always have a small C concern
right Right
I don't really have one. I think
they need players to develop
That's you know I think the big
big piece that often
gets left behind You look at a
team's offseason and you say
"Who did they add?" And that's
solely how much they improved
And to an extent that is true
You need to add add pieces that
holds But you know to me I just
keep going back to Drake May
year two in the system What's
that look like You know how does
he make his strides And can he
you know continue continue to
put the offense in position And
and of course the offensive line
is is a big piece of that So it
is all connected as we talked
about on on draft weekend but I
think I think they're in pretty
good shape I think think they've
put the pieces in place to
continue to build the foundation
to build this team long term
which is what you know we all
want We want them to be drafting
not for immediate need but but
for you know to continue to
stock and and have guys that are
going to contribute over the
next four or five years not just
here in 2027 So it does require
a little patience I think it's
just think think sometimes it's
a gotcha of like well how much
better are they and it's like
well you got to get there to
that point where you're you know
not always chasing your needs in
the draft you're you're building
for the future and building and
have a foundation so we'll see a
lot of these guys have to
develop will camp has to develop
jar wilson has to develop um you
know maybe some guys that we're
surprised about that's what gets
me excited is when somebody
maybe comes out of the woodwork
that you weren't expecting and
there's a lot of questions but I
think we know where the answers
will come from if guys develop
yeah if they don't develop okay
well now you're back to square
one in some areas but they've
got what they think are the
answers to questions. Yeah that
I mean it's you know look some
guys are going to drop off too
You know that's and that you
have to have enough improvement
to offset you know, some like
line offball linebacker like I
don't know how much stock you're
putting in OBS or Obasor Yeah.
Uh six round pick I I'm not sure
how much much you're counting on
him to contribute on defense
right away So you know behind
Robert Spain you know h
how do you feel if he's not not
there And Teduca's point about
attrition and things like that
you know he's getting older and
he's position that doesn't
doesn't have a ton of shelf life
usually but other than that and
of course you know getting this
AJ Brown deal across the the
finish line. That's that's a big
one that sort of my thinking
going into the season is AJ
Brown's going to be on the team.
Yeah I think I I think that's
how we're all operating as long
as that is a little red red
space in there in the death
chart I have just and it's not
in bold It's got a question mark
and it's light. I think I think
he's going to play play the X
Deuce AJ Brown ready to commit.
Um yeah if as long as that
is happening then you feel
really really good about where
they're at I mean there's some
depth
concerns always You know I'd say
linebacker maybe a little bit uh
interior offensive line They did
draft a guard which surprised me
a little bit Um interior
defensive line
and you know get a nose tackle a
true Tonga replacement Yep But
there are some
guys out there I was looking
looking at it yesterday just
what is left in free agency that
this time of year teams might
say "Okay we didn't get this
done in the draft You know can
do they they go out and sign a
Matt Milano a Bobby Wagner One
More Season Swan Song type of
thing Do they, you know see
value
value and as we know guys become
available. Yeah. Guys who aren't
available now become
available later throughout the
summer. Certainly in August in
the around around roster cut
downs there'll be another
wave of there's a lot of nose
tackles out there too That's
like I feel like a position that
I mean it's happened a lot over
the years Car Carl Carl Davis is
a guy who came in a few years
ago and you know you need a two
down run stuffer There's a bunch
of guys in their early 30s out
there that have played a lot of
snaps that I just wonder the
difference is and I think you
look look across the league
every team has a position well
well if you lost this one guy
you don't have much but I mean
it's you're not going to have a
backup that you're feel great
about behind everybody Um but at
the same time I wonder if you
know would they make a move like
that before or would you kind of
wait to see if somebody got got
hurt and then all right we got
to go to the street to get you
know somebody. Yeah And that's I
I feel exactly the way way Mike
and Evan do in terms of where
the roster is right now That
doesn't mean I think they're
loaded across the board I think
that they have have answers And
probably more they I think they
have fewer question marks in
terms of starters than they did
last year I think we we kind of
know who's going to play Um you
know last year at this time we
didn't know Jared Wilson was
going to start at at left
guard You know we thought it was
chance, but I I think that you
kind of have pieces in place You
know where guys are going to
slot But the big thing that Mike
and Evan talked
about I think is the valid thing
is is which of these young guys
doesn't progress the way you
hope And then in turn what
kind of of problems does that
create Because there is you know
I I again I think
the roster is in a much better
spot than it was uh a year and a
half ago when this all
all started But the depth isn't
where you want it yet either So
if like like Trevon Henderson
and Jared Wilson you know just
does two guys off the top of my
head two young guys you know
they don't take a year or two
jump or you know show show any
more
promise then does that affect
trickle down You know does that
affect the offensive line You
know where do you go for center?
That's why I pointed out
interior offensive line line
because right now Ben Brown is a
good top backup but if he's
forced to start, you know what's
the
layer of depth depth behind Ben
Brown You know if Tucker goes
down if Wilson oru goes down and
now he's a starter for a long
period of of
time you know is it is it Kaden
Wallace Is it one of the Andrew
Rups, uh M you know like who
who's that next? Someone's got
his death chart open. Is
it uh you know they kind of
hinted you know vaguely at uh
you know Lamu
potentially playing a a guard if
need be Not his long-term
position but if they needed him
to kick inside as a backup they
might be able to do that with
the best five
five theory. Yeah I mean like I
think there's a chance that he
you know plays a little bit at
all four spots
you know not center But yeah I
think Paul you hit on something
good that was what I was think
think of and that last year we
said you know they haven't they
don't have depth Like that was
the big question Has their depth
improved You know is it better
this year And how much better?
Some spots spots marginally
maybe other spots not so much
But that's that to me again goes
back to my original point of is
this team building that
foundation that when you do have
to put somebody in. One One of
the questions you know we uh we
were asked you know for our
newsletter this week is do you
do you feel like the roster has
improved I think some an element
of that And I I do think you can
look at at you can definitely
answer yes I mean I don't think
you can say that it's gotten
worse You can't I think that's
the only option that's not on
the table It's either very very
similar or gotten better a
little bit. But I would look at
things like that like so the
safety situation last year at
this time was you know Kyle
Duggar and
Jabril Peppers right And then
all of a sudden it turned into
Craig Woodson a rookie fourth
round pick and Jaylen Jaylen
Hawkins So that's a big
difference It worked out They
played well I think Woodson got
better and better as the year
went on So now you have Woodson
with Kevin Kevin B who I don't
think anybody would argue
isn't a better player than
Jaylen Hawkins But what is he at
33 or whatever he's going to be
you
know at the the start Um and
does he stay healthy the way
he's been He's been an absolute
machine He's never missing. He
never misses games. Um so you
have to hope that that kind of
stays stays stays that way I'm
just looking and I have like
some of my stuff
He's missed like one game in 10
years. Yeah Like it's
ridiculous. Yeah. Yeah How
durable he doesn't miss many
snaps period like even
within the games Yeah. Very
durable player Oh good stuff
One one question I have is early
in the season they lost Gibson
last
year. So they were down to two
running back on a rookie How do
you
think this GM Miller can be the
third guy and and see time right
away
or will he be one of those
running backs that got get red
shirted or I think it's a good
call out for it I think he'll
have a chance to um I'm going to
write his profile so I have
watched a little bit more of him
Um you know he's had a c a
couple good games last last year
Um but I think you need three
running backs. Yeah I just I
don't know if he's a kick
returner too And that's almost
like I feel like the third
running back you'd you'd love
him I think they'd love him to
be a kick returner I'm not sure
that that's going to be I think
he might have it like cuz to me
he's like got more more buildup
speed than he does like instant
acceleration So like when when I
watched him I that was just my
takeaway is okay once he gets
moving he's got 442 speed which
is same as Travon Henderson like
he he can run at a pretty good
good pace but he has he's not
exactly like instant to that in
terms of his acceleration So on
a kickoff you have this whole
you
know kind of runway runway to
build up to that speed He's got
size he's got some girth
to him like he's pretty sturdy
Uh so you know know the concerns
with him were
a lack of burst You know he
doesn't have that initial burst
to kind of get the edge or get
up into the second level and
third level And uh maybe maybe
some vision between the tackles
concerns pass pass pro like a
lot of young running backs the
mo the UDFA that they signed
Montgomery uh reportedly at
least there are some people that
think he's better than
Jan Miller So I I've I've seen a
couple of people on on the X
that have said that
the better they got got the
better running back as a UDFA.
Alabama was a weird team last
year Um they couldn't run the
ball Yeah. Um and that was a
problem all year A lot of people
use that they they they use that
as a defense of Tai Simpson You
know too much of the the burden
was on him and then once he got
banged up a little bit they had
no running
game to fall back on And you
know Jim Miller I believe was
like a three yards per carry
kind of guy
guy up for Alabama which you
know they have a first round
tackle that got just got
taken in Proctor. So you would
think that they would be be one
of those teams that they can
always run the ball but it was a
weird weird year for them last
year. Yeah Yeah He uh he gets
some knocks for his vision
between the tackles and and
couple games that I watched of
his I was
like I mean there's not that
much place to go like you know
especially against some of the
better teams like Georgia and
stuff like that I don't know
there's not there really aren't
a whole lot of space out here
for him to to go but I I think
that he's got some of that that
buildup speed or that you know
once he gets up to a top speed
he he carries it pretty well
that maybe he could be a kickoff
return and he covered kicks a
lot early in his career at
Alabama
as an underassman He covered a
lot of kicks too So you know
you've heard some you know maybe
a little bit smaller but a
little bit faster like Brandon
Balden type vibes with
him that he he can be a pretty
big special teams contributor
and then maybe like a
you know emergency running back.
So what's the number on on the
roster right now in 87?
87 And who are some of the
people reported that they signed
off the street? Sure I can Uh,
are we we counting them or No.
Yeah I'm counting counting the
UDFAs They're at 87. So they got
another six holes right So you
know to Evans
UDFAs They're at 87. So they got
another six holes right So you
know to Evans point, you got got
93 now 90. Why did you come up
with 93? I don't
know. It's like 90 95 93. You
have 91 with an
an international a IP player So
they technically have 88 bodies
but they
have only 87 counting against
the the roster. Uh Germany or
something
Yeah he's Lawrence Mets Yeah he
came in late last year Um but
but they did you know to Evan's
point about the guard position
they did sign uh or have
reportedly signed two
guards Jacob Rizzy and John
Darius Morgan Um they also
signed a
a tight end Tanner Arkin and
four wide receivers Jimmy Kibble
Cameron Dorner Kyle Dixon Nick
Tjaniro one running back Miles
Montgomery Deon mentioned
mentioned defense a little bit
lighter on the undrafted guys
David Blle up front and we
watched a little today Uh and
then
quarterbacks Channing Canada and
Kenneth Harris Uh so a little
you know the wide receivers a
little bit intriguing to me I
mean they got shoot they got a
bunch of wide receivers right
now I mean they got 10 10 11 I
mean 11 I think not counting a
potential potential AJ Brown
move.
Um you know I I was just
interested in how those guys
kind of differentiate themselves
Um one you know DJiro D Jaro
looks just like your favorite
Paul Those like scrappy
scrappy slot receiver type Um
Josh Bubby I
please fall fall in love with
something different. The one I
was kind of interested in was
Tanner Arkin though from
Illinois who um is 63 and a half
two two and you know ran a four
uh
no sorry that's the sorry that's
the tight end Um Um give me a
second you were going to say 488
I was like wait wrong guy wrong
guy wrong guy uh no it's Dixon
below him so it's Dixon Culver
Stockton really small school kid
but 6'2 uh four uh 624 you know
I mean
6'2 and a half uh 220 you know
ran a 451 He's he's a big
contested receiver kind
of guy So it's you know an
interesting kind of of
compliment to this group Of
course you know John Giles
unfortunately for Paul got got
got the the let go yesterday as
they as they brought guys in But
um yeah we'll see. Be tough for
any of those I mean there's four
wide receivers Do you make
anything of that though Does
that sound like a big number to
me I feel like I've been doing
this long enough that I should
have a scent at camp 10 or or 12
right Yeah Because you need
those guys to run around. I
think that they didn't they
didn't draft one Yeah. So Elliot
Wolf said
that you know they'll be be
active in the UDFA market at
wide receiver because they they
decide not to draft one So they
threw some darts in the UDFAs
Dorner I think is anything
you know We'll see Um you know
he's got a little bit more He's
not
fully Paul's uh you know what
you hate
I was trying to to try come up
with word the right terminology
for
that He's got a you know some
ability Um you know Montgomery
the running back I've heard some
good things
things about as somebody that
people thought was going to get
drafted. My friend Lan Larrison
still in the picture. Sure is
Yeah. Got got got my haircut or
Barbara cuts his hair. You
would like to buy real estate on
Land Larrison Island it's
available It's
going. I have have beachfront
property so you can't you can't
have you can't have the private.
I like that he's staking his
flag early though Not looking if
you want like you know there's
there's access right off the
ferry ferry
Airbnb maybe. But if you have AJ
Brown with Romeo Dos Dos and
then
let's say M Hollands. God bless
you. Um, and Lan
L Larrison out of the but I'm
I'm trying to go like so that's
three. Yeah. Then you get into
Demario Douglas Kesan Booty
Efton Chisum Now we're up to six
And Kyle Williams is seven.
Okay. Now fully anticipating
somebody somebody
goes you know not get cut but
someone goes like in a trade or
something
like booty has been been
rumored, you know throughout
this whole off season.
Um just just those guys in in my
my view are probably camp
bodies I don't see I don't see
an avenue for any of them to be
more than a practice squad
option.
No I think the back that F
brought up I mean the two
running backs the running back
has a chance of all the day
three I mean we just recorded a
kind of a draft rap Uh and
that's just you know there's no
pick in the fourth round So it's
just a easy dividing line
between the top top three guys
And then you know as Evan put it
kind of the special team shots
But of all those special teams
potential guys I I do think the
running back is is is one spot
where you know maybe maybe
somebody could emerge There's
also just a lot of bodies at
cornerback You know can any of
those guys you know
Chuck-E-Crees might be back and
and maybe he resumes that role
that he had last year But is
there any other Marcela style
Kobe Miner Prunty from this year
Any of those those guys that did
I say that? Fun to say you
nailed that one at least. He's
got some NFL experience you know
kind of like a Charles Woods
type you know but uh I watch
Prunty I I kind of think that
he's also here
to play special teams to be
honest Me too. Uh but I actually
saw saw him as maybe somebody
that could play a little safety
uh if they wanted to develop him
on defense but
Ryan Cowen made it sound like
they're going to start him at at
corner I just thought that
he was a little bit raw at
corner but he's got some length
he's got some size he's got some
long speed and he's
actually a really good der Like
that was probably the one thing
you know blitzing off the short
side of the field that I was
like "Okay that that's got some
closing speed uh you know some
some aggressiveness so in the
blitz some timing Uh so that was
probably not exactly what you
want to
hear is that your corner is best
going forward So uh you know
that was probably the thing that
that stood out to me But that
was sounds like a safety. Sounds
like a safety and also sounds
like a guy that'd be pretty good
on special teams right If he can
kind of do the space I just
think Marcela's dial like you
know a little bit bigger rangy
versat uh versatility to play
both corner and maybe you know
on special teams That's what it
kind kind of I'm thinking
of in my mind. Yeah, maybe
that's what they're envisioning.
He had some issues with thing
you know just like double moves
Like he'd bite on every time a
quarterback would hit him with
with a pump and a stutter it
would just me bite on it You
know things like that that he
needs to clean up But
he's got got some raw
measurables that are intriguing
especially on special
teams Uh so we'll see But you
know they probably need I'm
I'm assuming that they're
looking at Charles Woods as a
guy that's going to be the
fourth cornerback if all goes
well. Yeah. And then the fifth
guy if there's a six the guys
are going to be 90%
of any snaps they get are going
to be on special teams So, the
quarterback room though I I like
I I don't really have any
concerns Like I know some people
are
are crazy about the debt at
corner I mean when you have
Christian Gonzalez Carlton Davis
and Marcus
Jones you you feel pretty good
about the quarterback. To me it
would only be um in in Carlton
Davis's um durability. Oh
Christian Gonzalez is too a
little bit. Yeah that's a
good point Good point Mike.
Little bit. We don't talk about
I like to be a little bit more
positive but no, you know
somebody's going to be injured
in training camp you know. Yeah.
No but I mean Mike is right
Gonzalez has missed time in all
of his seasons. You know people
forget
last year because it was early
in the year and then he was just
like there the rest of the way
But first three they went one
and two without him Yep Boom. Ow
My hamstring You know miss time.
That was so That's not time.
Sure. They lost
two of of them. Wow Easy Taylor
could have gotten the number
one. I'm just saying don't
throw don't bring him. Oh you
just Yeah that that cut to the
bone right
Don't be mean. I love you Taylor
I actually really do I've grown
to really really like you a
lot. All right What What else do
we need to uh put on the table?
Anything Well just probably that
we'll see all these guys next
week rookie Indian camps next
week Um you know
Lomu I think will come in on
Thursday Um, I think all of them
are coming Thursday. May May 7th
is the day they all come in and
we'll have uh access to the
first round guy
out in the field like they
usually do. Yep Up the jersey It
be interesting to see like
rookie mini
camp just I guess act uh raran
but like
you're not going to be
evaluating the trenches in
rookie mini camp right Right
Like
so rarely know I want to see
what he how big he looks on the
field how he moves famous
Morton to Raridan connection I
think they do have a quarterback
they they drafted It's not no
offense to Ben Woolridge but
it's not Ben Woolridge There was
another
one Um, who was that kid? And he
he struggled. Well I just
remember Ben Woolridge like
would take like the snap
behind the the play You'd like
go through the motions of like
playing
and everybody is like like got
all crazy about it and I was
like what a hard O like
go stand stand on the sideline
with everybody else dude. All
right Uh that reminds me of Mapu
What he used to do
play sad depressed marte moo
walking out to the my. He was
mopy. I think Drake's going to
play quarterback probably. Yeah,
good spot for him. Drake? Yeah I
think he's got
a spot. I think he's probably
probably going to make the
roster. You going to pencil that
in? Yeah Milton
will probably be the three
technique Yeah you know, you
know as we've talked
about as everyone everyone knows
that's the key to this year is
what what kind of progress can
he make Drake? Yeah it's just
the offense right I
I mean that's the NFL now You
need an offense You need a
quarterback who who knows what
he's doing And
I guess I'm just so much more
interested in it situationally
just because what happened in
the Super Bowl Bowl and and
really the playoffs because you
were so high on Drake May during
the season and he's the MVP
runner up And you know let's
face it after the performance in
the playoffs
and the schedule and all that
stuff like he's you know kind of
gotten denigrated for his his
performance last year And you
know that's if you'd ask me that
in in mid November of like well
you know the offseason people
are gonna kind of be like well
Oh we don't know Drake I I just
I
want to see him get back to the
level he was at and get that
confidence back and just you
know see what he looks like as
he really starts to settle in to
to this system that we talked so
much about puts on the
quarterback and you know how
much does the experience help in
this
situation We heard all the time
about Brady and Josh having this
shorthand of like remember this
game from 17 years ago you know
like this is what they were were
doing and this is what we did we
have to do something similar so
you get to watch Drake slowly
accumulate that
experience and hopefully he's
really able to become that chess
master this year and put put
himself and the offense
consistently into position to
make plays. Yeah I wonder how
you know to like flash laying a
foundation
of what like like their base
concepts are going to be
offensively They might have a
little bit more fun and freedom
this year to to expand on
different
things that maybe Josh didn't
major in in the past that he can
like moving pockets and bootlegs
and things like that that might
be a little bit more conducive
to Drake's playing style that
weren't conducive to Brady or
whoever he had Uh so I think
that's that's exciting because
you know they have four athletes
now You know obviously LMO is
probably not going to play right
away
but at least three of those guys
are are highly athletic athletic
blockers that are going to start
and if Lomu does get playing
time and he's at super athletic
too So like I don't necessarily
want th those guys like in a gap
scheme where they're trying to
like go downhill on people like
you would want
them to be more using their
their finesse and using their
speed and using their ability to
block in space a little bit more
uh then you know we're going to
run power and we're
going to block down and we're
going to pull the guard and the
fullback's going to
maybe we're two years away from
it because the Lumu is not going
to play right away but but once
he gets in like that's four
fifths of your offensive line
that are all elite athletes and
not necessarily like glass
eaters
like so how do you kind of
figure figure that out as well
will they
be an offense that reacts to the
defense or dictates what
happens well I think they have
versatility within their
personnel right
now that I mean they have a good
tight end room that I think
covers the bases pretty well
They've got a you know real
fullback now Um Um they got good
size quickness on the
receiver room I mean if you had
AJ Brown So I I think that
they're going to be able to do
you know what they want
to Adam I'm curious how how Mike
Vrabel said he challenged the
offensive coaching staff or I
guess the whole coaching staff
to come back with you know
creative ways to evolve How does
that manifest itself You know do
we see uh uh those things You
know obviously not anytime soon
but you know in training camp
what what else do they have I
just I think that they're
getting more of their guys in
place to be able to do do the
kind of things that we know Josh
McDaniels liked to do during his
time here to do to do business
as business is being being done
What needs to happen this week
to beat this Seattle defense or
this Kansas City defense or you
know this remade Buffalo defense
Um you know I'm really
interested to see how
they how how they do it You know
a year after working with Drake
what new things does he feel
like You know things that I
thought last year before I
worked with him I don't
necessarily think or they've
been reinforced you know I I
just that's that's what's
exciting I Year two Year two
with Drake and Josh. You think
that they'll take that Super
Bowl and go over it again and
and say "Okay here's what we
should have done." I don't know
I don't know. They already a lot
of them said they watched on the
plane ride out and then buried
it. Oh I don't know I mean like
I I I thought we were talking
specifically with Drake and I do
think that Josh Yeah Mostly with
with Drake would would would
look at some of that stuff. They
used to look like days maybe
maybe months later when they'd
come in for the spring you'd
have all the low lightss and
they won the Super Bowl and he
has all the he has it queued up
for all the plays they they they
missed and didn't make So I I
would expect that they would I
mean I think that you kind of
have to because it's a copycat
league and like if
teams watch the Super Bowl Bowl
tape especially teams that
they're going to play early on
in the season next
year before they they really
start to declare who this team
is going to be Like you're going
to see the nickel pressure
you're going to see you know the
different different things that
Seattle did and you're going to
have to have answers to it I'm
sure that's what every team's
going to try to replicate
against him. I think they have
to do that I think I don't think
Dary that game I think they have
to use that game, especially
when you got to play Seattle,
right and say "If we had done
this we might have had a
different outcome." Yeah You
know I was just thinking kind of
a hypothetical It's like say say
Drake went out against the
Chargers in the first round and
it was like 3835 and they fell
just short here They got upset
in the first round but Drake
threw five touchdowns and just
looked lights out They just
couldn't get that like stop that
last field goal How much
different would you feel right
now Like you know what I mean
Like he got got to the Super
Bowl but I almost feel like you
would maybe feel and not right
or wrong just you probably would
be even more excited about Drake
if he hadn't won won those other
two playoff games if he had just
had a great gone out on a high
note like he had played most of
the season I know there were a
lot lot of factors with that but
I just think we sometimes lose
sight of the fact that the kid
went to the Super Bowl I know it
wasn't pretty you know getting
there and and there were
certainly challenges that he he
had to go through and I think
that experience will help him a
lot But I also think like if we
just ended that season and he
gone out and kind of finished it
like he did and we didn't didn't
win any like you probably would
be even more excited and I think
that's the level of excitement
that that you should have have
right now for him coming into
this year. People not excited.
Well you know what I mean Like
like I think it's tempered a
little bit based on you know and
maybe just because of the how
we'd be tempered when we have
you Exactly Paul And that's why
I'm here. I'm excited to go out
next week. I hear you I just You
know what I mean Like coming out
of the Super Bowl it's like like
think about the Drake May hype
train in mid November when he's
you know MVP Like literally
we're arguing for him to be the
MVP of the league versus those
three playoff games where you
know especially the last two
where it just you know he didn't
really do much and the offense
didn't do much. Should we at be
at all concerned about the
shoulder? Not anymore. No, I'm
not I mean I think you're always
concerned about quarterbacks
getting getting hurt and I'm not
concerned about any of this. I'm
not concerned about the shoulder
at all I mean I think if he if
it was something significant he
would would have had surgery on
it Well, that's what I think.
Like it's not like little
shoulder separation. Yeah I
don't think it's anything that
would linger into the season Um
I I have mild concern concern
about some of the stuff that
Mike talked about in terms of
how much was the drop off in the
playoffs related to
to just competition and how much
of it was related to hard
to parse it. Those defenses were
really good Yep. You know and
you don't face a
a lot of defenses that that are
that good. So I expect him to
bounce right back and be where
he was if not better. That's you
know, Yeah I just think the
playoffs but I just think the
playoffs in general in all
sports are kind of a different
animal And
like that was his first taste of
playoff football And And the
fact is is that because they got
breaks in the defense and this
and that they ended up winning
anyways in spite of
it but like Justin Herbert's
still trying to do it Well let
me say let me say it this way So
like if they had played Buffalo
in the playoffs and they lost
3835 I wouldn't have this this a
similar kind of you know but
if they had lost to Buffalo in
the playoffs say you know 28 to
16 I'd
be like hm that's a drop off you
know like they didn't
move the ball and score as many
points against Buffalo as they
did say six weeks earlier when
they lost that game here
in Foxboro um same defense yeah
it's the playoffs
but now I be I would have
different concerns I look at it
as the Chargers the
Texans the Broncos and the
Seahawks I don't think you see
that caliber of defense every
week You could make an argument
those were the best four
defenses in in football last
year Um you know maybe the
Patriots Patriots would have
been in there as the top five
That might be the top five
defenses in football. I don't
think you see that every week.
Yeah. No but again I don't know
Sure Was it just about the the
opponent or out. That's
what I'm saying in terms of the
like because you're not going to
see that every single week
So So yeah maybe once they get
back to the playoffs we might
have the same questions but
they're not going to have to
face the Seattle defense. No but
I want I want an offense that
you know you don't win every
time you play the better
defenses but you have answers
for the better defense It's like
the Red Sox when they play the
other team's best pitchers they
can't hit You
You know I so I want to I want
to you know have success
against the better defenses Yeah
Not all the time but I know what
you're saying You know I just
think in
sports sports in general like
most of the time the superstar
athlete has
failures before he finds success
And Drake May maybe kind of like
stumbled stumbled into some su
success in the playoffs by the
defense carrying them and all
that kind of stuff But most
of the time you don't have have
Tom Brady who comes in in year
one of the starter wins the
Super
Bowl Usually you get knocked
down you get knocked down and
then eventually you break
through I mean Justin Herbert
and Josh Josh Allen are still
trying to do it. Y you know like
they're they're eight years into
this thing and they still
haven't done it, you know So I I
I feel
like like that was his first
real taste of it and all of them
like Will Campbell too, you know
that was their first real taste
of Yep when it goes up a level.
Yep Their hope is that they get
more tastes That's not a
guarantee. Yeah. All right Uh
855 Pat 500
is the hotline
Podcastatriots.com
Podcastatriots.com is the email
address Uh Brandon writes in uh
he's from Vegas by way of
Lexington um writing to get your
thoughts and grades on the
rest of the ASC East draft
classes There seems to be a
general consensus that the
Patriots went
about for course landing a solid
solid B in pretty much every
article I've read I I
give him a BB+ right Sure Is
that that what you guys gave
him? Yeah. Yeah, sounds about
right on the heart Uh that said
opinions on the other three AFC
teams seem to be all
over the place I've seen grades
ranging ranging from A+ all the
way down to C minus for each of
them
What do you guys think? Uh I
have not seen anything other
than A's for the Jets. Yeah
Jets. The other two I I would
say were not as wellreceived
Buffalo and Miami But the
Jets by all accounts I mean did
very well. They also had three
first rounds Yeah Right I mean
that's all these grades like
when you're picking you know
31st in each round versus
picking where the Jets were
picking like it's obviously
indicative
of that The Bills one I think is
a little controversial Um you
know TJ Parker
uh you know kind of similar
player to AIS not exactly the
same similar kind of of player
Uh you know they didn't draft a
receiver until they drafted
Skyler Bell in the fourth round
who maybe should have gone a
little bit higher but um you
know I'm kind of on the fence
fence about that one
too but I'm a tough grader when
it comes to this. I was a little
surprised they waited as long
for
skilled guys just, you know and
and then then the receiver is
more of kind of what they
already had You know I don't
think it was a bad draft per se
but I think I I've seen seen
some different opinions on
Buffalo and Miami I think the
Jets did well Now again you it
hasn't been their problem. You
have that that
capital I mean you're right It
hasn't been their problem It's
it's the other stuff. Um but you
have that
capital You should come away
with some good players that
should be able to help your team
right away You had three three
first round picks I would expect
those guys to play. I think on
on Buffalo it felt a lot
motivated by changing their
defense and you know needing to
get new different pieces right
right around exactly how that's
I'm trading up for the the the
Ohio State corner I thought was
I'm not going to try to
pronounce his name I I thought I
thought that was kind of weird
Um I don't know I got Bill's
fans mad at me about Skyler Bell
so I should probably stop
talking. I also thought it was
all like didn't they have a lot
of trade downs early again which
is which is what they did last
year too Like
I I think they need need talent
I think they need an infusion of
talent They're not as they're
not as skilled as they've been
in the Josh Allen era And I
think much much like city I'd
say the same thing about the
Chiefs. Yeah. I don't think they
did enough to sort of help that
def that talent deficiency. Yeah
Skar Bell is I just think an an
interesting player for them Like
I I can see I when I watched him
I I did see like they the Bills
fans
all think he's the next Stfan
Stfan Diggs right They they see
a similar player You could make
that case Like there's shades of
that in his game but But to me
like Cleo Shakir is
a is a pure slot receiver That's
a guy that's lining up in the
slot you know the vast majority
of the
time I think Skylar Bell can
play off the ball a little bit
and move around around a little
bit more than a guy like Shakir
can Uh but he's not he's you
know 5'11 you know he's and he's
got some some press coverage and
physicality concerns plus the
level of competition Like I just
didn't see
a guy that was going to be that
was going to be really an
outside outside numbers receiver
Now maybe that's DJ Moore in
their for them you know, going
to have to be, but like it feels
to me like like they kind of
zoned in on like the separators
Like they want you know speed
and
separation and they're
sacrificing a little bit of size
and like like physicality And
it's just it's just interesting
to me because I feel the same
way about Kansas City and I
think think it's like the the
cautionary tale of the late
Brady Patriots of neither of
Kansas Kansas City
or Josh Allen They both have
elite quarterbacks who are in
their prime and the Super Bowl
window is well Fred you know
might not disagree but mostly
open. It's already too late for
Buffalo, but But it feels like
they're kind of they're punting
on trying to get the weapons And
you
know it's it's one of those
things I mean Joe Burrow is
lucky He's you know really good
two to start start with at least
But you know are they are they
doing a disservice to their
quarterbacks at this point And
you know did we learn something
from how it went with Brady
where and some of it look you're
trying you're just picking the
wrong guys So it's but doesn't
really even seem like they're
trying to invest that capital to
get them. Yeah If you told me
when they when you and I had our
original argument argument on
Buffalo with DJ Moore, if you
had told me that DJ Moore was
going to emerge from the
the entirety of the offseason as
their best receiver I wouldn't
have fought back probably as
much as
I did. Yeah Um I'm surprised
that that they're content that
that's okay We got him You know
and Shakir is our number one
receiver in terms of volume But
I like like Khalil Shakir a lot
He's not that guy. He's not like
a number one receiver that's
He's Yeah He's not dictating
what the other team's got to do
do the night
before. Yeah. I think the
Patriots showed you that they
can make him sort of an
afterthought
pretty easily. Yeah. Um doesn't
mean he's he's not a good player
He still catches passes and
makes some plays but he's not
capital T capital G that guy.
Yeah And and how much can you
lean into Cook I mean he he was
outstanding last year but you
know it's we know running backs
have a shelf life and
there's not there's not many
Derrick Henry's that do it every
year, right And he's and he's
smaller than him you know So I
we'll see I mean I'm not Look
I'm not arguing that the Bills
should be doing they're doing a
great Bills but I I would worry
that they're going to run out.
I'm not as familiar with What
exactly did they Well so they
drafted Kaden Proctor in the
first round which I wasn't crazy
about but I and I thought the
rest of their picks were really
really good They got drafted uh
Jacob Rodriguez Um they drafted
somebody else to biking on Chris
Johnson Oh is actually a late
firstrounder cornerback from uh
Yeah he's a good player I
thought they did really really
well I the Proctor pick was a
little bit which makes sense
that you get a new coach in in
halfley defense oriented Take a
couple of you know guys that
should be able to start right
away away for your defense And
the receiver they took
too was Johnson. I don't even
Some people had him like outside
of like the top 25 25 receivers
in the draft and they drafted
them in the third round. The
burner right Caleb Douglas Yeah.
So that one was a little bit
weird but to swing on Chris Bell
who we talked about I kind of
like I like that
one. I don't know I like I would
like that more for a better team
than Miami who can to you know
he might be be able to play this
year but if he can't it doesn't
hurt like
like the Patriots or the Bills
or someone like that But you
know Miami needs him They just
had their roster tore tore down
besides besides
Achan So, I mean three
linebackers though interesting
Two you know Jacob Rodriguez
that that Ev mentioned but
you know Traymore and Kyle Lewis
in the fourth fourth round talk
about the Patriots not picking a
fourth in the fourth
round. Felt like that was the
price they might have paid to
have to to trade up to get get
lomu and to get AAS was that we
lost the fourth we lost our
fourth round
picks and that's where the
linebackers really went Maybe
that was a sacrifice that
unfortun happened. Yeah Treymore
is kind of like a hybrid like he
can play on or off the line of
scrimmage Lewis is a a
nickel/safet like kind of
different too And then Rodriguez
Mike you
know he's gonna be a classic
Mike I with the Bills I wonder
wonder Casey Conpsion went a
couple picks ahead of them and
they traded out of the round. So
I I wonder if then they then
they went and ahead and drafted
Skyler Bell who's kind of like
discount discount Casey Conpsio
So
I kind of wonder if maybe they
were hoping that KCC was going
to fall to them and then when he
didn't they got got cuz I
thought they were going to take
a receiver at the top of day two
I thought they would be taking
an early receiver whether it be
the first or second round I
thought for sure they would add
one. But I just wonder if maybe
once they got to that point it
was kind of like
Denzel Denzel Boston It wasn't
there wasn't that separator that
they seemed to be gravitating
towards So maybe they just just
said our guy isn't here. You
know the another team I want to
bring up is just the Browns who
I heard a lot of people praising
I mean of all the guys we talked
about this whole process I
feel like like the Browns just
have like a bunch of the guys
you know that we took We know
they got a lot a long way to go
but um they got Conpsion they
got Boston the other Utah
Utah quarterbacks, 10
quarterbacks They got Talon
Green too Um you know Joe Royer
who's a big tough tight end
Justin Jefferson the the
linebacker um and Austin Barber
who who who we both really like
We talked about him a lot tackle
who can maybe move around So I
don't know I mean the Browns
they've had talent before and it
never seems to work out.
Favorite draft exercises Fred
And this is not directed at you
too It could be if you wanted
to. Yeah that's fine Guys tend
to love drafts that are filled
with players that they love.
Yeah sure They're they're
familiar You know what I mean
You have an eye for this you
know Uh oh I I I I I
loved him Uh you know I would
have have thought he made a lot
of sense for the Patriots in
round two And you know then
someone takes him and they
automatically had a good draft
cuz they took a guy that this
feeds into the uh I don't know
if you guys have noticed there's
like a debate on social media
going going on about big. I'm
sure we'll talk about this on on
22. You know it's like the media
consensus big board is not the
same as the team's consensus big
board. The teams don't have
consensus big big 32 teams Uh
but so
there's been like studies just a
cliffnotes version of this
There's a media con consensus
board that takes all of the
Daniel Jeremiah's and the Dane
Buglers and the Mel
Kypers and they put all those
boards into one consensus board
to get a general idea of where
the media sees all these guys
And then
the league obviously all 32
teams have a different different
board because there's different
they have different
parameters different schemes
different whatever So they have
all different boards and so the
league
people are are pushing back on
the media people saying "Well we
can't just do a blanket
consensus because we have
different par you know each Each
team has different uh you know
archetypes of molds of players
that we're looking for So it
doesn't work that way But then
the media is
pushing back and saying well if
we look look at the different
ways we can evaluate players
just in terms of you know
analytics and stuff like that Uh
Uh we actually can
see that the media consensus
board especially in the top 100
actually does better
than the league Now once you get
out of the top 100 the first
three rounds rounds the league
does well much much better but
that's cuz they have all the
information and all the time
that you know the media doesn't
have have on day three So the
media does at least as good as
the league in the top half of
the draft So there's a lot of
back and forth right
now on on the value of consensus
boards and does it actually
matter because all these
grades that you come out of the
draft are mostly based off of
what you thought about the
players before
the draft. So if you're going to
give a team an A because they
drafted on consensus but then
you're going to give a team an F
because they reach like the ners
are getting getting killed for
drafting guys well above where
everybody had them projected But
you know who
knows Maybe they're they're
going to be right and
Stribbling's going to be a star
and you know everybody was too
low on them. Well it would kind
of make sense to me that the
media consensus board would do
better you know because the the
like you said the team one is so
specific. Yeah
Right So one of the things that
I saw about this was some push
back and I I forget who it was
It may have been Joe Banner Um
one of those
types like like a XGM not still
in the league pushing back that
like sort of the consensus board
doesn't exist Like teams
teams don't you know teams have
teams have their consensus
boards but they don't look at
like
there's not a consensus board
that like you know John John is
looking at and saying "Yeah I
know that this guy
is is 70 on the consensus board
but we have him at 20 and we're
going to take
him. This guy I think it was Joe
Joe Banner who was former of the
Browns Eagles He's been around
Um he claimed that that really
doesn't
exist And then there was some
data that showed showed the
teams that reach the
furthest as Evan was explaining
from the consensus board are the
ones that ultimately do the the
worst. Yeah. In the draft And
it's kind of been proven over
the last handful of years
when you do that when you take a
a consensus board that's it It's
strictly numbers It's not
opinion but right? It's there's
a consensus board that has this
guy
at 75 and you took took him at
30. Mhm. So like that's 45
spots difference Like that's a
big gap. Yeah.
And do you then go from that and
then say "Okay that guy ends up
not working
out." That's what happens when
you reach that that much And
that was sort of the
takeaway that I was reading and
I was really interested in it
because it was good back and
forth like well I think the
industry like good pettiness by
the the XNFL guys good you know
good defensiveness by the the
the Evan types that that were
backing up the media. I think
the the the part about it too
that the media the argument the
media is trying to make on top
of just the evaluation part is
is uh you know how you're using
your resources like so if the
consensus is that this player is
actually going to go at 125 but
you took him at 35
well could you have had had that
player and another player at 35.
Right
Which is always my argument with
Bill. Right So it's you know um
evaluating sort
of like the the cost
effectiveness of that pick So
you know the Niners
the last couple of years have
not drafted particularly well
well and they're getting killed
by the general media for
reaching on picks like
Stribbling was the t first pick
of the the second round Most
people had him in like the
middle of the draft and they
took him as the first pick of
the second round the 33rd pick
in the draft So that that's
that's really what it comes down
to is okay well could you have
picked somebody more on
consensus at 33
and still gotten your guy
dribbling in the third round
round and you would have had
both to bring it home for the
Patriots Go to to is it 22 with
Cole Strange? Yeah. You know you
could have taken someone at 22
and gotten Cole Strange in the
third fourth round if you
believe the the consens the
consensus or even the second
board isn't worried about losing
out on a guy we really like The
you know
like what the team board is what
are they going to do Do we have
to move up here to get our guy
guy because we think another
team's you know like so they're
they're thinking about things
that
the media consensus board may
not be be thinking. And there's
no doubt that like we don't have
skin in the game like they do So
like if a a GM drafts bad over a
series of a couple
of drafts they're going to get
fired If a media person has a
bad couple of drafts they're not
going to lose their job
likes Vernon Gold Gold and Aaron
Maven and that don't work out I
just come to the draft the next
year. I think that pressure is
is a big difference right
getting
it right And what Fred's talking
about is if you risk losing the
guy, then if you lose him and
then he goes on to be a
superstar then that's going to
be held against you 855 pass
500 is the hotline Let's go to
it Sabah is in North Carolina
What's
up? Hey there gentlemen It's so
nice nice to hear your voices
and see you guys on the TV I
kind I hate that I haven't been
calling in I keep missing it you
know and I get
busy and I get in my meetings
and everything So that's okay I
just want to give a shout shout
out to you guys. Thank you. And
say to y'all do a great job.
Thank you Appreciate Appreciate
that. I have a couple of
concerns I'm so excited about
the season First of all and it
is true there's two seasons
There's football season and then
there's waiting for football
season So that is absolutely
true. Second thing is I am
worried about about the Patriots
Obviously my
guy Drake May I'm worried two
things Is the the um offensive
coordinator going to adjust the
offense to fit him more In other
words he's not Tom
Brady He doesn't just sit back
there like a statue He needs
needs to move around And Drake
needs to stop going deep on
every play Okay It's like he
wants to play the
hard eight every time he does a
craft You got you got to to do
the pass line once in a
while Dink and dunk That's what
happened to him in the playoffs
He wasn't dinking and dunking
enough and he was holding the
ball not having the line to
protect looking deep and and
then he'd get sacked So I will
those two things hopefully will
improve this year Then my second
concern is everybody
everybody else I mean you still
got San Diego The waiters aren't
going to suck private They got
Kirk Cousins now You got to have
Buffalo Buffalo still
Jacksonville Texans uh
Cincinnati's going to be back
because I don't think Burrow's
going to be hurt all year again
You've got the Coast is um
Daniel Jones His ankle's
probably going to be better now
Like where is the spot
for the Patriots to actually win
games that are quote you know
cloud of gimmies or easy besides
the Jets in Miami So I'm really
worried that just by attrition
there's not going to be room for
the patient to even make the
playoffs even if they're not a
worse team. No I hear you.
Reacting to those things.
There's no doubt the the
schedule's going to be tougher
These other teams, you know
you're judging by how they were
last year and maybe they'll be a
little better but but the
Patriots are going to have to be
a little bit bit better too Yep
If they if they don't get
better, then Yeah you're right
They're they're How many times
do we hear Bill say it If you're
not getting getting better
you're getting worse Yeah. But
but so Bob what if what if what
if
in your first part of your call
what if Josh Josh McDaniels does
adjust What if they move that
pocket What if they take
advantage of Drake What if he
starts to take a little bit more
underneath to answer when
pressure comes Now all of a
sudden that's to me that's
a big leap for the offense And
now you're competing with those
teams that you just talked
about. Yeah. And And those pass
rushers that you got to fight
they're going to get tired now
They're going to get tired I
hope to god their Campbell is
better I'm glad. So you're
winning the game in the fourth
quarter because they're they're
tired. Yeah, exactly Can I make
one more
comment You guys were talking
about reaching for draft picks.
I don't believe believe in that
To me if I pair pants that fit
me and they're expensive I buy
the suckers There's no need to
get a pair of pants that don't
fit that are cheap So to me if I
I want a guy I'm going to get
him I don't care what round it
is If he's there and I want him
I'm going to get him because buy
once cry once. What if you buy a
pair of pants and they're not
good good pants? Yeah. Or what
if you buy the pants? Yeah but
if they don't fit, what if
they're too short They cut off
like high ankle. Well they might
fit but what like you go you you
wear them once and they they
rip. Yeah Well then there's
cheap Talk about you buy the
good I mean if we just knew
where all the good were we'd all
be much better at this Thanks, I
just don't think there's a lot
of examples of teams that say
you know what I didn't really
want to pick Mike Do but you
know I did. Like if if you pick
a guy can we just operate under
the general assumption that you
like him? You got her guy. I
would hope so. I mean
I I'm not telling you that every
pick is the same You know you
don't like every single pick
pick the same There's some
guys that the entirety of your
organization is 1,00% on board
They love Drake May They're
going to take Drake May with the
third pick and and everybody's
in agreement There are other
guys that I'm sure there's
disagreements on, but I don't
think there are a lot of guys
that the team just looks and
says "I "I don't want but we got
to take somebody Take them."
Like I don't think that happens
Yeah, there's got to be
something about the player that
attracted you to him to take
him, right Yeah All right Um
time for a break Uh when we come
back we got a lot of emails
There's some good ones coming in
I'm just scanning through Good
stuff We got
more calls Everyone's excited
Why not Why not Hope Springs
Eternal right Let's go. Even the
Red Sox won three in a row. Come
welcome our
newest restaurant restaurant
additions at Patriot Place
Estella brings a celebration of
flavors with a modern fusion
menu exciting cocktails and
brunch available available daily
beginning at 11
Enjoy freshly brewed coffee and
Mediterranean inspired breakfast
and lunch from Angel's Cafe
Graving the classics Chick-fil-A
makes it easy to grab your
favorite favorite with mobile
through carry out and dining
options Download the Patriot
Place Advantage app for special
offers and to earn rewards every
time you visit Patriot Place
Shop dine enjoy. The
heaviest metal credit card of
all time Wielded at business
dinners like a
samurai sword It's a classic
corporate power move but the
real power move having end to
end visibility on your most
critical shipments FedEx the new
power
move. Whether you're in the game
or betting on the game you'll
need a game plan DraftKings
Sportsbook the official sports
betting partner of the New
England Patriots provides you
with everything you need to
build your personal betting game
plan so you can get in on all
all the action while practicing
safe bets Visit Visit
draftkings.com/responsible-gaming
to learn more
about all the safe betting tools
DraftKings has to offer Hope is
here 800
800 327-5050 or gambling
helpline ma.org must be 21 plus
play it smart from the start
gamesensemma.com physically put
it in in Massachusetts
see
draftkings.comresponsible-gaming
for details and
state specific responsible
gambling resources. Isn't it
time to get get exactly what you
want Welcome to Red Hot Deal
Days from Verizon where you get
your pick
of our best deals like my plan
where you can pick the perks you
want and and save on
everyone For limited time bring
your own phones to a Verizon
store and you can get my plant
for our best price ever Get
exactly exactly what you want on
your phone plan and only pay for
what you need Bring your phones
to your Verizon store today and
get my plan These deals won't
last It's your your
DraftKings is all about
responsible gaming It's more
more fun when it's for fun So
play responsibly DraftKings the
crown is yours. Gambling problem
Call
1800 Gambler 21 plus Age and
eligibility varies by
jurisdiction. Ryan it's good to
talk to to you
Uh real quick how do you think
the draft has gone so far
Draft's gone
great Look it's always an
exciting time of the year and
it's been a pretty pretty
exciting couple days Um every
draft's unique and so uh this
one's had its own
unique appeal appeal and
situation So it's it's been uh
you never really know what to
expect and that's that's kind
of the unique and fun part about
it. Ryan last last time we heard
from Mike he had shared that he
would be in communication with
you guys And ESPN said today
that communication's been
constant Can you just describe
what it's been like and what
it's done for the room room uh
to still be in touch with Mike
during the draft today. Yeah our
focus you know Mike Mike and and
the organization put out
statements about you know Mike's
situation and and our support of
Mike And I would just say
everything we've done at this
point our our preparation for
the draft has allowed us to
operate in a manner just as
normally as we
would. Next question Doug Ky Ky
Hey Ryan thanks for doing
this Uh I want to ask about
Demetrius Crownover Do you guys
view him as a right
tackle only Do you think he can
can move around the offensive
line at all Uh just how do you
view his his
flexibility? Sure Demetrius is u
you he's a
massive massive individual You
know he's got great length Um he
really has
um some pretty natural pass
proability I think ideally you
know his with his size
I mean both tackle positions
inevitably the tackle position
is
it becomes left and right in
your ability ability to play
both sides Um and I think we
think Demetrius can can
contribute contribute on both
sides of of the tackle
position. Thank you. Next
question Mark
Mark Daniels. Hey Ryan Uh this
is the second straight year you
guys have drafted um two
tackles Um I guess my first
question is just can you go into
detail with your experience and
how difficult difficult it is
to find young quality tackles
and how much has that played
into you guys being aggressive
the last two years in the draft
Yeah that's that's a great point
and and
it is a premium position in our
league and the pool of players
that can play the position is
is is relatively small and you
can never have enough depth I
think there and the emphasis we
want to talk about or that we do
talk about in protecting the
quarterback
it starts up front and we've
talked about that I think a year
ago We talked about a little bit
of an
inside out mentality and u you
know it's when we see talent at
the tackle
position I think we're always
going to look to add as I
mentioned before before we we we
kind of always look in in free
agency in every avenue to try to
build
the offensive line and and
Demetrius presented it himself
um you know tonight when we were
in the draft it was
just a a value of a player that
we thought we wanted to add into
the room. Awesome Thank you.
Next question Ian Still Still
Brian thanks for doing this Uh
one more about Mike Rabel Is
he on a call throughout the
entire day with with the draft
Is he chiming
in from time to time Just a
little more specifics as to his
involvement
today. Sure I think as I stated
already you know um obviously
it's public knowledge that Mike
was not
going to be uh here today That's
that's been stated And as far as
his interactions I think that's
that's part of the stuff that we
would keep internal here about
about how today operated and
and how we were able to But we
were fully confident that with
all the work that we've done and
and all all the
preparation that he's aided in
throughout today um that we knew
today would be able to operate
um um in a in a manner that we
can help build his vision this
football team
and um I know he we he has our
full support as well He has
ours. Next question Sophie
Well. Hi Ryan Thank you so so
much for doing this Um I'm just
curious
with your last pick Um know that
linebacker was a need for you
guys
going in to add some more depth
there What What was it um about
Namdi that stood out? You know
with Namdi he's um you know he's
got an
interesting story He started out
at Iowa Iowa Western and you
know has really worked his way
into
um a good player TCU and was at
the Senior Bowl and really good
testings and and I think as as
we look at it and we evaluate
these guys from a couple
different angles from
defensive perspective a a
special teams especially on the
third day uh
you know our special teams
coaches took a look and had a
lot of positives to to say about
Nominee's projections as as a
special teams player and and
that's important at the
linebacker position as as you
know and so we thought he fit
the profile of that and we're
excited to work with
it. Next question Alex Bath. Hey
Hey Ryan thank you for doing
this Um you guys talked a lot
about versatility I'm curious
with Karan
Prunty Uh do you guys see any
safety versatility with him He's
somebody you just see playing
playing cornerback. You know I
think those things always will
kind of bear them you know play
out as the as the players get
here Uh I never like to put too
many many expectations on a
player being able to multiple
roles or you know down the road
stuff But with Karan he's a
player that was
really intriguing us to us
because because of his his
length his speed He's an
aggressive player Again has an
interesting story U starting out
out at Kansas and he um you know
went to North Carolina for a
minute and then at Wake Forest
and
you know we brought Karan in on
a on a 30 visit He did a great
job job with our coaching staff
He he really represented himself
in a in a really professional
manner and we're excited to
bring his skill set um at the
perimeter corner and where he he
goes from there I think that
will will just be once we
get on the grass and start to
make those But I think ideally
right now you know he's
competing at the corner
position. Next question
Greg
Madon. Hey Ryan Um just hoping
you could um help me Like you
guys are really
heavy at at tackle now Like is
James Hudson going to be inside
Um
you know just sort of you know
where are you sort of slotting
those guys Is Lomu now with with
Kron over here Is is Lomu going
to work more left tackle to
start It just seems like it's a
crowded tackle room at the
moment. Sure If I would want a
room to be
crowded I'll I'll take that as
being one room that's crowded
just uh based off what we talked
about before and how hard it is
to find you know tackles in the
in the National Football
League You know again a little
bit of that was just trusting in
the in the
board Um when we get to areas on
the draft and we have have
players valued in certain ranges
And you know with that one we
leaned into a guy who between
where we had things
stacked he was one of the the
better players remaining on our
board So there was a value there
We don't ever know what's
going to happen tomorrow the
next day So that's why you stick
to a concept of the best player
available when you you pick even
if it if it today looks crowded
that's not going
maybe be the same in a week or
two weeks or by by the time we
get to train camp So that's kind
of the situation
there Greg is you know those
guys go in the room and compete
and um when you take the best
best player sometimes it may
look it on the front end but
those tend those tend to have a
way of working working out. And
now great moments in
history. But Fred what tastes
tastes better a tender or a
wing? A wing if if
it's done right because the
skin's still on it and it's
fried and you know it it's all
from
one chicken. I think I think the
bone gives it it extra flavor I
don't know why. Well the it's
the fat from the
skin that that gives it the
flavor you know. I like bone in
but I there's times times that
Hey, I'm perfectly satisfied
with my tenders like when we do
it right here right
Because I don't want to be
eating wings and making a mess
as I'm trying to yell at college
college for telling me that
I call Bellichic a mediocre
coach. You know it's on your
face but it's also all in your
fingers and stuff you know So
when I eat wings at home after
it's done I just put my hand out
My dog cleans my fingers. Just
hangs his hand off the throttle
You fat bastard You can't even
get up and wash your own hands.
Not
immediately Yeah Watching TV you
let the dog do the work. Oh my
god. Not
yet Not yet I'm still working.
You know he likes it You know
it's win-win for both A little
spicy forms that give him a
little That's another great
moment
moment from I don't understand
why that's such a big deal I
don't know Anyway, can't
be good for the dog. All right
855 past 500 is the hotline
Podcastatrius.com is the email
address Lots of emails and phone
phone calls Let's go to the
phones Todd is in North Carolina
What's up Todd
Todd Todd is gone. Todd
Todd. Todd had to get back to
work Sam's in North Carolina
We've had three North Carolina
callers in a row What's up? Sam
is gone. Sam All right Hey
what's up? Oh no No There he
is There's What's up Sam? Hey Um
I I just wanted to reiterate
what Duce was saying earlier I
really feel feel once Drake May
mastered the system
and learned to take the We have
that problem again. He just hung
up I don't don't what what
happened All right. He just
the moment the IT guy walks we
got to the bottom of it. Yeah
Just wanted wanted to read it.
Ben Hershey Pennsylvania writes
"Over the past few years I've
created an
annual ritual of sorts where I
watch the live network draft
coverage and then listen
back back to the Patriots.com
coverage a day or two later.
Knowing Knowing who the picks
were
makes the late listen even more
exciting as I anxiously await
the panel's reaction I can
almost smell deuce sweating
through my headphones each time
time an edge defender got picked
in the second round knowing the
whole time that AAS would be his
new guy.
Yeah Uh all that being said the
best part of this routine is the
comic relief provided by some of
the sound bites For example I
don't think they like Eli Rarin
Maybe they like Eli
Rarin Probably not Or Paul's
bemoning the prospect of them
trading up in the first for an
OT who won't play his rookie
year before the trade has even
been made Then he talks himself
into the I I can see it once the
pick is in I told my wife that
it's like watching Game of
Thrones That was true. It's like
watching Game of Thrones with
someone who's never never seen
it while I know the
entire story and I get to enjoy
their reactions He called me a
loser. Anyway please Please
don't take this as criticism
Anyone who expects you all to
get the picks right every
time doesn't understand ball So,
thank you. Well we were
right that that the Eli Raren
one was not did not sound like
that was universally
right I just heard from Ryan
Cowen moments ago. I I think
healthy debate Eli I mean um
Elliot Wolf and I think they had
sort of admitted there was some
healthy debate Um and I don't
take any offense at all because
I did that I did exactly what
what the the
emailer said I was like I don't
really want to trade up for a
guy who's a left
tackle and is kind of insurance
and is going to red shirt shirt
a year and then give up
resources to do would And then
they did it and I was like "No I
understand I can see what they
did That's totally what I did.
That was that I think that's the
hardest part that I have with
the pick It's not necessarily
Caleb Lomu It's just the the
process of you trade it up for a
tackle that's going to red shirt
and you just drafted a tackle
two years in a row now And it
just I that piece of it I'm just
just not. But I also look at the
board and I'm like "All right
well what else were you really
going to
do?" I know in that spot. So I I
understand understand the
immediacy of it He's not going
to play right away hopefully cuz
Morgan is here But you can't
complain about you need
to protect Drake May and and
Morgan's not going to be here
forever and then you address it
and then you complain like I'm
like I
I get it think this guy's going
to be your right tackle for you
know five years
it's a good pick. Well then then
but how can you think that how
can you know that
you don't you don't know
anything about any of these
guys? No but I'm saying
specifically he hasn't played
that position That's what I
would would push back on. But
that's the plan that but the
reason why I didn't love the
plan is I He doesn't play right
tackle. Yeah. But that's why I
didn't love the the plan
initially Now again Email was
right I talked myself into what
I got there I got there I got on
board Um because I do do
understand and it's kind of what
you guys gave me push back on
like I think it actually does
set them up nicely and it
provides a layer of insurance
where now they can let the the
strong survive The best player
emerges as the left tackle and
then you worry about the right
tackle
later Um so I you know like I
said I did I did the email was
right for calling out my
hypocrisy I I talked myself into
it. So change your
mind minds. I always say it's
better to sort of be a little
bit
flexible than just stubbornly
set in your ways like like
heaven. Nate's from
Iowa and he said said he played
football with Eli Rarin
Uh and I could not be more
excited that we drafted him I
know he wasn't some of your your
guys' favorite
tight end of the draft but is
definitely the toughest of them
I played strong side
linebacker and I remember going
against him in practice deciding
that I need to become friends
with this guy otherwise I'm
going to get killed in practice
for the next four years He's a
great guy and you guys are going
to love getting to know him When
do rookie rookie jerseys become
available to buy Because
I'm 100% getting his. Yeah. So
you'd have to So I think when he
when he says custom he meant
just just to to cover I would
say well I mean I
wouldn't what I would highlight.
What do you think he did against
Kenyan Sadik and Max Cla Like I
mean mean he he's telling you
what he did against you played
against this guy You didn't play
against the other guy This is
not how I would describe other
than bouncing back
from two two ACL's early on in
his life is that shows some
mental toughness for sure Uh but
but uh toughness on the field in
terms of like grit and
blocking and like I wouldn't
necessarily describe him in that
exact way but that doesn't
doesn't have good things things
about him It's just But maybe he
was tough and like tough to
cover. Sure. You
know, I mean he is tough to
cover there's a willingness to
his blocking and that to me me
what the appeal is is that he
can develop into an all-around
tight end who who can do I'm
intrigued by that pick. Me too I
think he can develop into an
allound tight end and I think
you know even now
when you see him get
opportunities that are a little
bit more favorable like blocking
safeties instead of blocking
defensive ends and stuff he does
a pretty good job So you know
it's just the he plays you know
he's 6'6 so he's a little
upright in terms of like his you
know leverage and all that
kind of stuff And he doesn't
quite have uh the the mass yet
you know to really like dig in
But I saw an interview with him
where he said that he wanted to
gain about 10
lbs you know play around 255 uh
in the NFL And I think that
might help. That's the size I
mean that's the size Like the
thing that kind of stood out to
me watching him a little bit
yesterday again was just like
good at tempoing his his routes
a little bit You know it's like
he kind of builds up a little
bit but there are a bunch of
times where he just kind of gets
lost in the the coverage and he
finds you know the open space Uh
but I'm just excited because I
think he can be protected this
year He doesn't need to come in
and and they're not going to ask
him to buck They're going to be
like you know and Evan you know
made a great point He's not you
know big red zone producer at
Notre Dame but but I think
that's where you start You know
you get in those red zone
packages you get two tight ends
and you know you see what you
can do with him off the seam I I
just I think that connection
with Drake is going to to be
something that I'm really have
an eye on in training camp just
because I feel like when Drake
sees a big body he is confident
to chuck the ball to that dude
And I think he'll be chucking it
a lot to Eli Baron. Yeah he's
got a nice complimentary skill
set to what the rest of the
group has You know Hunter Henry
is kind of your chain mover
steady uh you know presence
there And then obviously Julian
Hill is a blocking specialist
And then Raran's got some real
field stretching ability You
know a guy that averaged over 15
yards a catch So he's got got
some real vertical juice And
that to me is his path to
playing as a rookie is you know
he's going to bring a little bit
something different to that room
It might not be in a high volume
but just have some sort of
different element to his game. I
think uh Raridan is the guy to
me has the most potential to
exceed exceed expectations. Yeah
Yeah I think that sounds about
right. Yeah I mean Deuce is
right Like the way that Drake
May throws to
bigger targets whether it's the
tight ends like you can see a
comfort level especially over
the middle of the field that you
know okay if I have to really
really rip this one in there
like if it's a little high you
know this guy's got the ability
to go and and you know catch the
ball above his head versus
trying to hit you know a Pop
Douglas in the same window is
through the trees, right is not
as easy So he definitely has a
comfort level there. John in
Louisiana when When Evan knew
who the pick was for the
Patriots but it wasn't publicly
announced yet he was like a kid
at his birthday ready to blow
his candles but his parents had
to hold him back till the
birthday song was was over Also
Fred do the Cowboys feel like we
got our guy only in the first
round or do they feel the need
to congratulate congratulate
each other even on day three Oh
yeah They all do Yeah you should
That was a very unfortunate
byproduct of this draft for me
is is I every single team they
put up there all of
them couldn't wait to
congratulate themselves for for
every pick. Yeah I mean even if
when they make their
calls for the undrafted free
agents they they I I used to
really make fun of Dallas for
that Now everybody Yeah they all
do it. That would be an
interesting video of just
behind the scenes of the dash to
sign undrafted free agents and
what kind of negotiations
go on you know do hey I got this
much guaranteed money from this
team Would you be willing to go
up a little bit You know those
kind of things And and you know
what are the needs Like, keep
that in mind. Yeah Do we not do
we not We We didn't get this in
the draft we got to let's go
after this kid You know how do
they I think a lot of the UDFAS
too they look at the team's
depth charts that are calling
them because they need need to
have a path to make the roster
So they're not going to sign
with a team that is like loaded
You know the Patriots like why
would a a tackle sign here right
now Like you just four wide
receivers did. Yeah I know
That's right. Yeah but I that
might be the maybe the deepest
spot It might not have the
highest highest in terms of
numbers Sure. Yeah But I think a
lot of you could look at it and
say I was just making a point I
I understand you're like I valid
valid that every time we talk to
those guys afterwards like what
made you sign with
the Patriots And a lot lot of it
is to be honest like there was
an opportunity there Like I saw
you know
there wasn't a whole lot ahead
of me on the depth chart and I
thought I could make the team.
Uh Andrew in
Coronado California Few random
thoughts. Uh first I
like the Lomu pick We knew we
needed a tackle in the next year
or two so why not take one this
year
in what is is regarded as a weak
draft instead of next year when
the talent will be better at
more premium
positions and will be probably
picking higher Second the Super
Bowl run was great but it
delayed the offseason shows by
five weeks which kind of sucked
Third when Paul
talks normal he sounds like he's
from Boston When he puts on his
fake Boston Boston accent he
sounds like he's from
Philly and it's hilarious Oh I
didn't know that. Uh last
Chester can pull up. Do I do my
Boston accent I sound like I'm
from from Philly apparently.
So uh last Chester can pull off
a signature catchphrase
Christian in LA cannot Also I'm
pretty sure he's no way way
somebody with as much money as
he claims to have would
have given up Patriot Super Bowl
tickets to go next year He'd do
both There never was a
ticket Maybe Maybe he does live
in a big house as the man as the
nanny or something.
Oh Oh wow That's a good point
Like if you have that much money
you go to both, right Why Why do
you Well yeah. Like like my
uncle somehow has been to
like nine of them as a a fan. Uh
Another uh Carolina call This
one's from South Carolina It's
Dustin What's up
Dustin? Hey how you guys doing?
Good. Hey All right I got a
quick question
and a a statement Um so I'm
looking to really see a big jump
from
Kyle Williams this year Um his
skill set just just screams a
guy that needs to play on the
outside the majority of the time
Um so I'm prefacing this
question with the
assumption that AJ Brown will be
here and and Kan Booty will not
If that is the case um with
Romeo Dobs playing 82% 82% of
his snaps on the outside last
year do you think he'll be able
to transition to the inside or
do you think him and
Kyle Williams will will compete
for on the outside opposite of
AJ? Yeah. And then my statement
is is Fred do the right thing
Bring Andy home. Okay All right
Thanks
Dustin. I think dogs slide
inside when you go to three wide
receiver receiver and you know
maybe you bring in
Hollands on the outside you know
as a second outside presence or
um but I like the Kyle Williams
I think he's got I mean I think
he has an advantage in his speed
You know he's got young legs
He's got to get stronger I mean
that's something he's been
talking a lot about going into
this off season But I agree I
mean if I was a receiver in that
room I would say what can I do
better than anyone else here And
I think Kyle Williams right
now the long speed but and I
think he's pretty good getting
off the line too I mean I think
he's he's got at least quickness
Yeah Some good good releases So
uh but I agree I think that's a
you know it's not hard to look
at 2027 and think you know you
know you got Dobs and and maybe
you got AJ AJ Brown but if Kyle
Williams can be you know that
third guy um it be I mean look
you hit on a draft pick at a
wide receiver I think we're
gonna be throwing a parade
so all eyes on Kyle Williams
this summer I just hope he stays
stays healthy that he's
consistent You know that was one
thing last year that he did well
He was always available and you
know made the most of of some of
his opportunities but you wasn't
wasn't consistent in that But
again he's a rookie and hard to
expect more than that. We just
have asked the question like did
he not play more because of what
was in in front of him on the
depth chart and Diggs is here
and Matt Collins is here and
Booty and Douglas and or did he
not play more more because he
couldn't make that push
and make that turn for me Sorry
Paul to interrupt you I know
you're about to jump in But the
same question that Evan does. Is
he is he mentally mentally
knowing where to be and is he in
the right spots And that's a
concern I have with Pop Douglas
It's not a concern I have with
Keshan Booty I think Kesan Booty
is starting to get it and
understand how to run his his
routes and where to be But I you
know Kyle Williams as much as
get stronger mentally getting in
the right spots And you know
just simply and we talked about
this earlier in the show unless
major changes happen and guys
are not here that
are expected to be here I I want
like I wonder how does it change
for Kyle Williams from last year
to this year? In other words,
okay if Booty goes well you're
still bringing in Brown
and Dobs you know so for the so
booty and digs go
Brown and Dobs come in they're
ahead of Kyle Williams So now
you have to find
a way if you're Kyle Williams to
to get ahead of M Holland or get
ahead of Demario Douglas
and you know earn those kinds of
reps on a more more regular
basis. Otherwise what's
changed You know whether he's
inside outside or indifferent
he's not going to play outside
over AJ AJ Brown and he's not
going to play anywhere inside or
outside over Romeo
Dos. Yeah So who is your inside
guy Who's your move the
chains guy or Romeos underneath
guy Dos Dobs. But this guy said
he lined up
outside% of the time like Yeah
You don't have to be a a
downfield guy to be an
outside guy. But in Green Bay
like they they run a lot of
condensed formation So like
their
receivers are in tight into the
numbers Even if he's he's
outside he's still technically
Yeah it's inside the numbers but
outside the formation. Yeah Yeah
So there's there's some
blurred lines there I actually
like you know Digs ended up
being pretty much a slot guy
Like he was 6040 slot I think
last year But you know if you
look at like
where like a heat map of like
like where Romeo Dobs actually
was on the field
versus where Diggs actually was
It might log as a slot snap snap
for Diggs and a wide snap for
but like the real estate is not
all that ends up
right Yeah. Uh Tom and Nic like
like everyone I was thrilled
with the 2025
draft because the Patriots
didn't try to get too fancy and
instead selected players who
were high on all the consensus
boards But this year's Day Day
Three felt like they decided to
try to be the smartest people in
the room and they selected
players like Prunty and Abby
Azor who were considered
UDFA candidates by by pretty
much everyone in the league Very
frustrating I'm not worried
about those picks. I just Yeah I
mean she might be
right You know they might have
been reaches I I from everything
I read and this is kind of a
pretty simple
synopsis is that the NIL is
really impacting day three more
so than anything else And the
the theory that I read a lot
over the weekend was
whereas in the past you might
get let's say e let's say
there's 100 early
entries entries in a in a
typical year say eight years
ago you know at maximum only a a
third of those guys are going in
the first
round right So that at least
twothirds of those guys is still
available later in the
draft Well now if you cut that
number of early early entry say
in half there aren't as many
draftable players available,
100%. So day three is going to
get the hit
There's guys getting drafted in
day three today that maybe
wouldn't have been drafted eight
years ago
when everybody was coming out
early Now a lot of guys stay in
school They're taking the money
in school And I think that the
pool is smaller, 100% And I
wonder how much longer that'll
go on for like just two points
of that. It'll catch up because
well you'll catch up. I also
think that some guys actually
end up hurting their their
stocks by staying Yeah Because a
lot of time what's happening is
like guys have early
breakouts They stay for the
money in NIL and then they end
up having having a bad year you
know senior season Uh that and
when they were draft eligible
and they don't come out So I I
think in some ways ways we've
seen that actually work against
players cuz it's one more year
of sample you know of what and
this is the new normal too So it
will catch up and you won't
won't have those big early entry
classes you know like you used
to do But now this will
become the normal thing and
it'll it'll work work itself out
And you're right like look at
the two great receivers right
Jeremiah Smith who remains the
great receiver but but Ryan
Williams was the other one They
were both true freshman and by
all accounts would have been
like top 10 picks if they
come out after their freshman
year Smith probably is going to
be a top top three pick you know
when he comes out Ryan Williams
took a step back last year So if
he was draft
eligible after that that first
year he may have been what
Evan's talking about
May have been a guy who sort of
hurt his stock a little bit by
staying in. Yeah I forget all
the names but like a
a lot of the quarterbacks like
Drew Aller for example like a
lot of these quarterbacks uh you
know went back and they hurt
their stocks actually by going
back worse and you know
sometimes that's just
circumstance you know you lose
your team lost a lot a bunch of
guys to the NFL there was a
coaching change like whatever
the case may be that might lead
it there I I would also say like
with the day three picks I kind
of felt a little bit like the
emailer a little bit I kind of
felt like day three they they
sort of said we're yeah like
back into the roster special
teams he's right about where
some of these guys were
projected a lot of them were
projected udfas the one guy
today yeah crownover is the one
sort of like guy that was like
all right that was I I like that
pick a lot He actually I think
went below consensus right Like
he was consensus higher and and
went a little bit later than he
was supposed to go trading
completely out of the fourth
round even though it got Yomo
and and Ais maybe that ends up
working They were right about
that in
the long run But I think in the
fourth round of this draft there
was a sweet spot of some of
their their depth needs like
linebacker safety places like
that You know Duce let read off
a couple of the linebackers I
think was what Miami got right
Kyle Lewis you know guys like
that that went
in the fourth round and I was a
little disappointed that they
didn't have an opportunity to
draft those guys
So there's other like kind of
pivots like you know they went
and and they drafted the TCU kid
and like Harold Perkins was
still on the board when they
picked and I was I would
love to know like what what the
difference between those two
guys were for them And I think
some of it is is that you know
they kind of project Obizer to
be a better special teamer and
like you know that that's just
sort of where where they're at
right now I I don't know I
thought
that the day three of the draft
it wasn't so much that they
reached It was more that I think
they kind of were like "We don't
have any roster spots left that
aren't special special
teams you know depth guys." And
they kind of took guys that have
an eye towards you know playing
in the kicking
game." Jacking in in ABBA Uh
Fred is right Lomu will be the
Patriots right tackle for five
years or longer Lomu is a better
offensive tackle prospect than
his more
highlighted teammate teammate
Spencer Feno Why you ask Because
the Utah coaches moved the more
experienced Ferno to right
tackle tackle to put Lomu at
left tackle last season Did they
do that
because Lomu was a worse player
than Feno Because Because Lmu
Lomu has a better frame to play
tackle He is better proportioned
to add mass throughout his frame
especially to increase
upper body strength than Feno
Moreover Although Feno has elite
measurables at the combine
Lomu's measurables were still
above average Furthermore FO's 4
4940 is irrelevant 40 40 times
are nearly meaningless in the
evaluation of
tackles. Finally brace
yourselves Low Moo's arms are 33
and 38 whereas Feno's arms are
32 and an eighth So I will agree
with some
of the premise of the email
There were people that felt like
Lomu was a more talented
player than Feno Not a not a
more more polished not a more uh
you know pro ready type of
player and definitely not a
better finisher But in terms of
just raw measurables
and and athleticism people
thought that Lomu might have
actually
been a better prospect Now the
other thing thing about the left
and the right you know I I
mentioned during our draft show
I think a lot of that was who
was more comfortable switching.
Yep. And so they felt like Feno
was was more comfortable with
the switch than LMU
was So they left LMU alone and
they and they moved Fenel over
But I've heard the the take that
people think Lomu is more from a
raw talent standpoint
has like a higher ceiling than
Feno does. It's just Yeah I mean
And they got taken
what 15 20 picks apart Yeah Like
it's not like one went in the
first round and one went in the
seventh round right? You know
like Meu and Mark Bryant as as
an an an example the two
Missouri guys who had a similar
situation left and right that
will be remain to be
seen Did they they not want to
make that move because they
didn't feel like Momu could play
the right side or because they
felt let's leave well enough
alone. I I I don't know
I'm not on the Utah Utah
coaching staff but we'll find
out These things will sort
themselves out. That's certainly
what the whispers were Now the
the FO thing that I think stands
out that that makes him you know
made him go higher was just you
know he's more technically sound
right
now He's more polished and he's
he's got a little bit more grit
and like finish his game than
Lomu
does But uh you know Brandon
Thornne said that you know raw
talentwise like
like Lom was probably a better
prospect in that respect So
maybe maybe it ends up playing
that way in three years You know
it's not going to be that his
rookie year but it might be you
know down the line. Skinless
chicken Uh Brett and Lemonster
with the first pick there seems
to be two minds of thought on
this one Every article I read
most of the people
people uh that think he is a
great pick and give the
pick a B+ through an A rating
Those people think he is
replacing and the people
who who like but don't love the
pick expect that he's going to
do spot duty and maybe fill in
for injured players and
eventually is replacing Moses
which is closer to the truth
Which is closer to
to the truth do you think in
year one B
Yeah I don't see any scenario
that he just beats beats out
Will Campbell year one as a
rookie I'm not telling you it's
impossible but I don't see it.
Yeah. B is more
likely likely in year one What
happens after that Like when
Morgan Moses is gone when he
retires then I think you find
out out how that plays out. Yep
Yeah
Yeah When Fred was out I wrote
about TV shows from the 70s and
80s that had quicksand episodes.
Oh nice. Um one article said
they were as common as Christmas
specials Uh and Paul thought I
must watch obscure westerns that
WSBK block from
Ever Here are a list of few
shows that had quicksand
episodes Gilligans Island Get
Smart The Lucy Show Brady Bunch
Charlie's Angels $6 Million Man
Hardy Boys
Batman Night Rider and and Dukes
of Hazard Wow. I need a I need a
followup I need a follow-up I
need to know what Brady Bunch
episode had quicksand I I'm
I know the Brady Bunch I don't
remember any Quicksand Maybe it
was maybe Mr. They were out in
the
wild That's the only one I can
remember They were out in the
wild. Maybe Mr Hanolay told him
to stay away from the quicksand.
I've only seen one episode of
the Brady Brady Bunch It's uh
Joe Nameoth right? Joe was on it
The football one of course. Yeah
it's the only one of those. Ball
nowhere He didn't like the route
that Bobby Bobby ran on that. I
mean obviously drifting It was
horrible. Good hit Maria right
in the face. Well that's a
different episode Jesus Mike
What are we even even doing? Can
we go back to the Campbell thing
for a second I mean you're the
one I want to go back to this
because all you know I got a
little cranky about it on site
Uh we talked we just talked
about Lomu and FO
and if that situation might have
just been FO actually just felt
more comfortable switching I
think that's the only scenario
that I see this happening is if
they say Lomu is a starting
caliber tackle but he's a
starting caliber tackle on the
left left side. And Campbell is
more fluid and is more able
to kind of move over to the
other side It doesn't
necessarily mean I can really
really appreciate this
take. It doesn't mean I can't
like take is bad It just means
that in
order to get them both on the
field I know what you're doing
They have to They're both
awesome but how can they be most
awesome together? Exactly. He
didn't beat Will Campbell He
was just Will was actually
better better because he could
play either side. That is
the pol I didn't say he was
better I just said in order
order maybe they're their best
two tackles and the only way to
get both of them on the field is
to put Lommo at left and
Campbell at right because
because that's where
they're you know he's only
comfortable on the left side.
And if that ends up being the
case, great. Yeah you got two
tackles. Well a lot of you two
tackles one of which is
inferior playing the left side.
I don't like it. Not necessarily
Well, according to this theory
that the only reason why they're
making the change is because
Will Campbell can play play
either side and Lommo can't.
That doesn't mean he's not as
good at left tackle as as Will
Campbell. It kind
of does but but now you have two
good tackles. It means he's not
as good at right tackle as
Will K. No I I'm saying that if
he plays left tackle over Will
Campbell they thought he was
better at left tackle than Will
Campbell Evan is saying that
wouldn't necessarily be the case
which again I I really respect
because it's it's it's as Paul a
take
as you could ever have cuz I
won't lay down my sword I'm not
going to to I I'm 100% going
down with the Will Campbell ship
and I'm okay
with that Like I like them
pre-draft I like them when they
drafted him Fred's got it. I
like them
14 If those two guys are
starting a tackle and they're
both good players then you
you've done it right Doesn't
matter where. We've lived in the
weeds of this for the last like
you know three days days and etc
going back But I just think when
you take a big picture view and
you look back at the depth chart
of what they've added the last
couple years at the tackle
position when you go back to
thinking what they they were
rolling out on the field two
years ago I just feel generally
like okay I don't know how it's
all going to work out but I like
that they have a bunch of
options there they've got depth
they've got some athleticism you
know so maybe it'll work out one
way or the other but it looks
like it's going to be good for
the team long maybe not signing
any player who's ever played
tackle tackle like they did two
years ago was a mistake Like
we're going
to get I can't even think of his
name now Horror for Is that who
Chuks? Well he played right He
just had never played left No no
no I know that. He couldn't go
left.
But that's who they signed to
play left And then he pouted
Said I don't play left I play
right And then
retired to camp. Is there a way
honestly to evaluate who would
be better at left tackle tackle
in
camp like pri you know before
our our snaps are
real is there an honest way to
say "Wow this guy looks better
than that
guy." I mean I think there'll be
hints of it especially in
practices You know you get out
there you get a sense. Are
you talking like we even before
they put the pads on or like
Well no no no no no You know I'm
talking about the summer. Yeah.
Yeah. Yeah I think so But I
think ultimately you got to get
to games with the way that they
have it set up and the way
they've been talking about Will
Campbell short of an injury or
something drastic I think it
would be hard hard to make that
move before you get into games
and you know. So So that's like
kind of my question. You might
have an inkling that in the
summer leading up to the real
games you you say, oh my god
this guy
should be I mean maybe like I'm
just gonna eliminate myself I I
wouldn't be able to do that.
Yeah I don't think I would
either. I think it's hard I mean
unless there was not without the
benefit of watching the practice
back Like watching it live I
can't imagine I would be be able
to jump to that conclusion. But
plenty of people will jump to
that conclusion if like Will
Campbell's losing one-on- ons
and Lomu isn't you know and does
have to be be drastic like I'd
have to be watching those. Yeah.
Oh I'll do it for you It's okay.
I let I'll let Bard tell me who
won those. The one in the ones
in Minnesota last
last year were great We we they
let us like stand like right
behind the drill and I was
literally like standing like I
was in the the bucket and so
like did you get
hit? No but you can like feel it
a lot better of like when they
when they go
when they go bull rush like you
can feel it a lot better of like
did they actually would that
have impacted you like would the
quarterback have had to move
whereas when you're kind of
watching it from afar it's sort
of hard to tell like how far he
actually moved the guy you know
but
sometimes times you know you can
feel it And I remember last year
in Minnesota like Will Campbell
going up against Jonathan
Greener and just being like
"Okay like that's there's
nothing like like being Yeah
There's nothing like being field
level near the and
hearing and feeling that impact
It it's you know you lose that
uh in the stands or on TV You
you can't understand the how
they register
on the Richtor scale They hit.
Yeah The other thing that's that
that stood out from being field
level in Minnesota
was Trayvon Like he took a wheel
route up the side. I remember
you guys talking about that
and I just like I I he was just
shot out of a cannon
in that game too right?
Different speed. Didn't he have
a a long run in that a long
like catch and run in that? I
don't remember Paul I was
filling in for you I couldn't
properly I don't remember him
having one in the That's not
very comforting that he had the
kickoff return in the opener
opener against Washington. I
thought he had a long catch and
run in the game but maybe it was
just just the one in practice. I
mean even Brian Flores is like
kind of was like whoa Like that
was that's a different level. Uh
let's get back to the phones 855
pass pass 500 Williams and
Phillum What's up William? Very
good How you doing Keem Hello.
Yeah. Uh how you doing Hey
what's up Wayne? All right
Hey Um uh Elliot Well Jesus
Christ. Oh what's
going on over over there? Okay
Um Paul can
Paul Evan can you just make some
sense of this for me please So
yeah Paul. All right So you're
three
you have have three starters All
right So you got the tackle you
draft the uh edge rusher and you
also draft the tight end. So
wouldn't they be red shirts
because they got to get
implemented